Matthew Cullen

Penfield, New York, 14526 | 585-831-0531 | m23.cullen@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

Full Stack Web Developer

Experienced software designer with quality assurance and leadership experience. Possesses strong team-building and leadership skills. Serves as a team leader to manage problem solving issues on a weekly basis. Quick learner, collaborative and creative. Works well under pressure and adapts to new concepts. Strives to write simple efficient code and contribute to the community.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby | Rails | SQL | JavaScript | React | Redux | Python | HTML/CSS | Git | GoogleFirebase | Algorithm design and analysis
Linux | Data structures | MaterializeCSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Pet-Assistant Frontend Backend | Demo

Keep track of important dates and notes for all your pets

- Used React as the frontend framework to create a single page application
- Used Redux to handle state between multiple components
- Used css and javascript to create a responsive navigation bar and layout

Fortune Teller api/client Frontend Backend | Demo

Ask a question and let the cards answer for you with multiple tarot spread options

- Created a rails api backend with Postgresql to handle CRUD/DataBase
- Created a javascript front end to connect to the api
- Used bootstrap to create a simple UI design

Book Review App Ruby on Rails - Github | Demo

Signup or login with google to read, write and comment on book reviews

- Used rails for CRUD actions and to connect to a sqlite3 database
- Created a login system that allows new users to sign up with the site or login with a google account
- Used embedded Ruby to render views with data from the controllers

Virtual Bookcase with Sinatra - Github | Demo

Organize and keep track of your books with this virtual bookcase

- Used Ruby with the Sinatra framework and object oriented programming
- Created a login system
- Implemented proper MVC structure

CURRENT PERSONAL PROJECT

TWICE Fan Site Github

English/Korean fan site

- Using React/Redux to handle and display data
- Using Google Firestore/Firebase to handle login/auth, cloud database features and hosting
- Styling with MaterializeCSS

EXPERIENCE

Baker, Bruegger's Bagels, Webster, New York

06/2019 - Present

Bake bagels that pass Bruegger's high standard requirements

Quality assurance/supervisor, Harbec, Ontario, New York

06/2011 - 02/2015

- Worked as a team to communicate problems and ensure the correct changes were made
- Supervised a team of machine operators and parts runners
- Used measurement tools to determine the quality of various parts

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 09/ 2019 - 03/2020